

Adel Ferdjoukh

Software Architect

29 years



Toulouse, France



+33 695 55 89 13



www.adel-ferdjoukh.ovh



ferdjoukh@gmail.com

About me ——

I obtained a PhD. in computer science (software engineering). I worked as a researcher and university teacher in several labs in France and Austria. Currently, I am a technical leader at Altran in Toulouse. I am responsible of an R&D project and I supervise developers for client projects on Model Based Software Engineering and Agile Frameworks.

Skills —

Model Based Software Engineering

Java

Eclipse EMF, RCP

Shell

Agile frameworks

Project Management

Languages -

French, English, Arabic, Kabyle, German (beginner)

Interests ———

Travel, History, Geography and Sport.

Experience

since 2019 Software Technical Leader Altran Technologies

I joined Altran as a software developer in Model Based Software and Java. I became the leader of an R&D project. Currently, I am the technical leader for *Model Based Software Engineering* offers and I

supervise developers on client projects (eg. Airbus)

2018 Researcher & Teacher Technische Universitat Wien

I was conducting research on Model Driven Engineering and I gave

courses on Graphical Modelling in English

2016-2018 Researcher & Teacher Universite de Nantes

I was responsible of students groups for many computer science courses: programming, databases, web programming and I con-

ducted researches on Model Driven Engineering

2013-2016 Young Researcher Universite de Montpellier

I was preparing my PhD in computer science in *Lirmm* research lab and teaching computer science courses in the *Faculty of Sciences*

Education

2013-2016 Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

A Declarative Approach for Model Generation

2012-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

Specializing in Software Engineering

2011-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in Networks and Distributed Systems

2008-2011 Bachelor Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in mathematics and informatics.

[Notable Facts]

Publications 10 papers in journal, international conferences or workshops

Best Paper ICSEA 2017, Athens, Greece

Talks Montpellier, Nantes, Lille, Angers, Paris, Bordeaux, Washington DC,

San Francisco, Oslo, Copenhagen, Athens & Vienna.

Teaching +700 hours teaching in 3 universities and +10 different topics.

Industrials Airbus, Dassault, Safran
Certification Professional Scrum Master I



Projects

HQ Workbe. Architect & Scrum Master Airbus

Digital Transformation of HQ Data and Tools

IPad Technical Leader Airbus

A workbench for aerodynamics studies

Icing Technical Leader & Developer Airbus

A Workbench for Icing Tools & Data

Optimind R&D Project Leader Altran Research

A Model-Driven toolbox for engineers

Rumor Developer Airbus

Automate and migrate simulation tools

Grimm Architect & Developer Lirmm

Automatic Model Generator